# **Curriculum Vitae**

## YAQOUB YUSUF MUBARAK ALMAMARI

P.O. Box 2636, Postal Code 112, RUWI, Sultanate of Oman Tel: 00968 98993946

Email: <u>Yaqooub@yahoo.com</u>
Date of Birth: 02 June 1977

## **Professional and Personality Profile**

Professionally - I have worked in Retail for the past **21** years in which time I have developed as an individual and as a team player primarily through my efficient working practices. I have activity sort to develop those who have worked as subordinates and have been determined to support my self and superiors. I am result orientated and consider myself a 'leader'.

Throughout my retail career I have worked in what I would consider some of the most demanding retail concept environments and have achieved in all. I have progressed and developed as a professional retailer and maintain that I would be an asset to any professional retailer due to my diverse skill set and management capability.

Personally – I consider myself to be a flexible and very capable individual, who when given a challenge would grasp the initiative with both enthusiasm and vigor. I retain tremendous energy which serves to motivate those around me and ultimately culminates in successful business practices and environments. I am a strong communicator which has been tested and proven in retail market. Ultimately, I am a family man with strong believe and morale values and have the up most respect for people, culture and equality.

## **Employment History**

OCT2015- Till date:

#### Fair Trade LLC:

## Sales Development Manger -Oman

- Responsible of moving and training Omani National within the origination.
- Branch visits and audits.
- Setting guide lines to all Sales team and merchandisers.
- Helping sales team to achieve set sales targets.
- Managing sales team and merchandisers in different locations.
- Staff requirements and assistance.
- Support agencies Sales and HR support.
- Hiring and requiting employees with the support of HR.
- Conducting training programs for all sales team.
- Guiding and motivating sales team.
- Problem solving.
- Training of new Khimji candidate.
- Market Audit and servicing.
- Identifying methods of smooth operations logistic, merchandising and stock.
- Minimizing issues of stock losses of controlling market expiry.
- Reporting to GM all needed reports and attending sales meetings.

# FEB2010 to Aug2015 Majid ALFuttim(Carrefour Sohar)

Started as Manager on training then moved to section Manager in hot food.

## Main position:

#### On 2013 being promoted to Store Receiving Manager -Service Head

- Fully responsible of all stocks coming in and out of the store.
- Controlling data movements on system and stock receiving of all goods coming as per LPO generated by commercial department.
- Managing stock in and out in terms of documentation and hygiene policy.
- Fully in charge of imports validation/claims.
- Making sure of smooth stock flow at receiving points with scheduling delivery timings for all goods in every day process.
- Maintaining hygiene records and temperatures control of goods and receiving point.
- Inventory planning and cleaning schedule for store rooms.

-

# Sep2007 to Sep2009

Sultan Center LLC - Based in Oman

Position: Hard Discount Manager \_ NIZWA / Mawaleh

- Reporting to and in conjunction with the area Manager Oman
- Developed and responsible for the of the business plan for a new Hard Discount store concept in Mawaleh.
- Responsible for the set-up of new stores and merchandising it.
- Working closely with the new staff and consulted on there issues from an operational point of view.
- Responsible for sourcing and employing Omani local staff.
- ❖ Compiled product category portfolio for convenience Discount store project = 750 − 1200 SKUs food, non food and general merchandise.
- Sourced entire product category portfolio primarily local to Oman but 30% internationally.
- Working with the Administration Director and the instigated of the personnel structure
- ❖ Instrumental in organizing and facilitating staff recruitment seminars
- Responsible and accountable for the store operations.

#### **Achievements:**

- Opened the first hard discount store in Middle East as Nizwa Store manager.
- Sourced and negotiated actual product range with a projected gross margin of 25%
- Successfully recruited personnel to facilitate new Hard Discount store for all job functionalities
- Successfully opened the first supermarket

With a sales area of 14,000 sq. feet and a projected turnover of RO 5,500 per store.

#### June 2003 to AUG 2007

## **Al-Omaniya Financial Services:**

- Senior Debt collector :
- Responsible of Debt collecting and the rest of legal assignments.

#### **Achievements:**

- Staff of the year 2004.
- Made the highest scour in collection thru out 2003 to 2006.

# Aug 2000 to March 2003

## Franchise Supervisor: Sanad Project

- Responsible for running 10 stores in different places in Oman.
- Looking after stores cleanliness and availability.

## MARCH 1999 to AUG 2000

**BP EXPRESS** 

**Positions: Store Supervisor** 

- Responsible for running a 24 hour Convenience store (during the operation, covering all aspects of the business, including overseeing the store replenishment teams, health & safety of both customers & colleagues
- As my role included looking at all aspects of the business to improve performance levels & maximize profitability in all departments to ensure KVI's were met and exceeded, with the major focus on wages costs, wastage controls, store spending & inventory controls amongst others
- Working with department teams to train and assist in the implementation of working practices

#### **Achievements:**

- Store sales year on year double digit growth for the last 3 years, YTD before leaving running at +5.5% YOY
- Absence Rates have reduced from >5% to below 2%, (company target <3.5%)</li>
- ❖ Labour Turnover have reduced from >60% to <25% (company target <35%, calculated on a rolling 26 week period)</p>
- Reduced wage cost by 15%, with no productivity implications to the operation, through effective personnel planning
- Reduced Inventory losses down from -1.8% to -0.63%
- Success store refit and remerchandising program, through which sales still increased despite all the disruption

#### May1997 to March 1999

**AL FAIR** 

# Position: Grocery and Front End Supervisor

- Responsible for the running of two department, ensuring challenging targets were set and achieved
- \* Responsible for recruiting, training and developing store assistant teams
- ❖ Took a 'hands on ' fresh food retailing, leading by example
- Fully responsible and accountable for availability on my department and remerchandising around 98% of the store within 2 month period

#### Achievements:

- Increased turnover with less store wastage.
- Reduced wage costs from 3.9% down to 3.0%, across the department.
- Increased productivity of the department.
- Reduced waste costs from 1.6% down to 0.9% across the department.
- Managed and implemented successful stock take plans.

## December 1996 to May 1997 MUTTRAH COL STORE -MQ Position: Grocery Supervisor

- Responsible for day to day running of Grocery department, making sure targets were met and exceeded
- As Grocery Supervisor I also deputized for the Store Manager when he was out of the business
- Sourced & Negotiated improved cost prices for regular product lines

#### Achievements:

Achieved highest sales profit result throughout the company, sourcing and implementing new ranges into the store exceeded set sales target by more than 75% on a regular basis.

## SEP1995 to December 1996 MUTTRAH Cold Stores Position: Butcher

Responsible for day to day running of sales of meat and fish department, covering up cashiers, organizing customer orders, back store organization.

#### Achievements:

- Staff of the year 1995 from Retail MCS.
- ❖ Increased sales of the department by 25%.

## **Education**

JABIR BIN ZAID SECOUNDARY SCHOOL 1995

#### **Professional Qualifications:**

Retail Sales OCT 1995-MAY1996
Fundamentals of Supervision JULY 2001
Ministry Of Defense – SEP1992 till FEB 1993.
Supervision and Management – MARCH 2003
Basic Fire Extinguisher – FEB 1999

#### Computer skills:

Microsoft office

Jawa system

Aurora system

Scmads

### References:

## On request